你找我吗
You wanted to see me?
我想知道为什么
May I ask why
自从我掌管这个基地以来
You have not filed a single mission report
你从来都没交过任务报告
Since I assumed command of this base?
因为我不交任务报告
'cause I haven't given you any?
我对这里作出了一些新规定
As you know, one of the changes I made around here
其中包括了每位组员都必须写任务报告
Is to require every team member to file mission reports,
而不是只有组长或者科研人员要写
As opposed to only team leaders and science officers.
真的?
Really.
我一点都不知道
I didn't-- I didn't know that.
我来这里的第4天就宣布了
I announced it my fourth day here,
是在一个小组的出发准备会上
At an away-team orientation meeting
对任务协议书作出的细节变更
Detailing changes to mission protocol.
我参加了吗
Was I there?
是的  这个会议是强制参加的
Yes. it was mandatory.
好像我不太记得...
Because I don't remember--
我看到你的
I saw you there.
老实说  想无视你还真有点困难
It's kind of hard to miss you.
我的意思是
Look, my point is
你在每次任务之后要写任务报告
I want you to file a report every mission.
我不擅长文笔
I'm not good at writing.
我预料到你会这么说的
I figured you might say that.
用这个
Use this.
这是数码录音机
It's a digital voice recorder.
对着它说话  我们会把它连上
Speak into it, we'll plug it in,
然后你的报告
And your report
会被自动记录下来  然后生成文档
Will be automatically transcribed and filed
和别人的放在一起
With the others.
我也不太擅长说话
I'm not good at talking, either.
不好意思啊
Oh, I'm sorry.
我跑得太快了点  老兄
Too fast for you, buddy boy?
我刚接到疗养院的电话  罗德尼
Nursing home just called, rodney.
他们想要回那个滑板车
They want their scooter back.
滑板车?  我那引擎盖下的可是
Scooter? that is a tri-cell li-po pack
三组的锂离子电池
Under my hood, son.
对不起了  是我不好
Ooh, sorry. my bad.
我要把你踩在脚底
Yeah, I will trample you.
别被你自己的裙子绊倒了
Well, don't trip on your skirt.
没事吧
You okay?
他差点就掉下来了
I could have dropped him!
对不起  我不知道这里会有人
Sorry, we didn't know anyone was around.
你真的没事吧
You sure you're all right?
话说回来
Come to think of it,
你在这儿干嘛
What are you doing down here anyway?
我在哄图门睡觉
Trying to get torren to sleep.
我发现抱着他到处走最能让他安心
I find that walking him is the best way to calm him.
他害疝气了吧
Ooh, he's colicky, huh?
凯勒医生说这些症状会消失的
Dr. keller says it's a phase that will pass.
不用担心了  我小时候也得过疝气
Oh, don't worry about it.I was a colicky baby too.
你就学我妈那样好了  让我哭到睡着
Just do what my mom did,which was let me cry myself to sleep.
反正又不会恶化
I'm no worse for it.
反正
Anyway...
我们是轮流抱他走路
We usually take turns walking him,
但迦楠去视察民情了
But kanaan is away visiting our people
他要不在好几天
For a few days.
我很想帮你  但好像
I'd help you out, but it looks
你已经把一切问题都解决了
Like you've got everything taken care of.
是的  我现在正要把他带回房间
Yes. now all I have to do is get him back to my quarters
不能吵醒他
Without waking him...
更不能被汽车压到
Or being run over.
我们不玩了
Yeah, we're done here.
我们就快结束了
We're just, you know, finishing up,
真的
Really, so...
晚安
'night.
晚安  好梦
'night. good one.
冲冲冲冲冲
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
我好像把马达用过头了
I must have put too much strain on the motor.
得给轴上一点润滑油
Shaft needs a bushing lube.
干嘛
What?
这算什么意思
What's that about?
不知道
Beats me.
瑞迪克
Radek?
进来
Come in.
指挥室  我是麦凯博士
Control room, it's dr. mckay.
东区停电了
We just lost power in the east pier.
怎么回事
What's going on?
怪了
That's strange.
除了指挥室之外
Lights are out all over the city
整个城市都停电了
Except the control room.
搞什么啊
Why is that?
麦凯博士
This is dr. rodney mckay,
呼叫指挥室
Calling anyone in the control room.
请回话
Please respond.
肯定是出问题了
Something's definitely not right.
罗德尼  你在吗
Rodney, are you there?
谢帕德中校
Colonel sheppard?
什么都用不了
Everything's dead.
我们没法调查出了什么问题
There's no way of knowing what the hell's going on.
好吧  里维斯
All right. hey, rivers.
分散行动
Fan out,
尽可能多找一些船
Find as many marines as you can,
向控制塔上进发
Work your way up to the central tower.
如果你碰到伍尔希的话就通知我
If you run into woolsey, let me know.
通讯设施瘫痪了  我们用对讲机
Communications are down. we're on walkies.
瑞迪克
Radek!
罗德尼  怎么回事
Rodney, what's going on?
什么  你也不知道?
What, you don't know either?
我准备去控制塔
I'm on my way to the control tower.
还想和你通话呢
I tried to radio you.
除了控制塔之外
Power's out
其他地方都没电了  给你
Except for the central tower. here.
你干脆去主电室
Go to the main power room instead.
看看是不是能重启一下电力系统
See if you can reboot the system from there.
好的
Okay. all right.
All right.
是谁
Hello?
罗德尼  听得见吗
Rodney, do you read me?
听得见  瑞迪克  你说
Yeah, radek. go ahead.
我试过重启系统
I've tried to restart power.
但目前一点都没进展
So far, absolutely no success.
那零点装置呢
What about the zpm?
我检查过了
I've checked it,
还有Naquadah发电器
As well as the naquadah generator.
它们都没联机
Neither are online.
肯定是有人在控制室里把它们拔掉了
Someone must have disabled them from the control room.
如果是这样的话
If that was the case,
他们自己也会没电的
Then they wouldn't have any power up there either.
他们可能用的是外接电源
Not unless they're using an external power source.
听我说
Okay, listen to me.
你也试试这么做
I want you to do exactly the same thing.
启用临时补丁
Initiate a temporary patch
连接外部电源
Using an external power source--
就是那个辅助电池组
One of the auxiliary battery units.
可以  但这点电源维持不了整个城市
Yes, but that won't be enough to power the entire city,
根本不可能
Not by a long shot.
这你别担心
Don't worry about that.
只要给我能启动主机的能量就行
Just get me enough juice to access the mainframe.
我们去查一下
We can figure out
那里到底出了什么问题
What the hell's going on up there.
好的
All right.
你现在在几层
Whereabouts are you right now?
36层?
Level 36?
35层
35.
太好了  35层
Oh, great. 35. perfect.
只剩28层了
So just another 28 floors to go,
只要走走楼梯
And that's just this stairwell.
就能到63楼
And then we get to level 63,
穿过一条辅助楼梯
Got to cross over to an ancillary stairwell,
再往上爬4楼
Climb another four levels--
只不过是到了星门室
That's just to access the gate room...
这样
Ooh, you know,
你在操作的同时
See if you can route some of that power
看看是不是能
To the transporters
把传输机的电源也接上
While you're at it.
好的  我试试
All right, I'll try.
这扇门是通向星门室的楼梯  是吧
This door leads to the gate room stairwell,right?
是啊
Yeah.
也许在停电的时候
Well, maybe the door was already closed
这扇门就是关着的
When we lost power.
这门是故意被关死的  好让我们不能进去
It was sealed on purpose to keep people out.
什么  你是说有人在入侵亚特兰蒂斯?
What, you think someone's infiltrated atlantis?
罗德尼
Rodney.
说吧
Talk to me.
我启动了临时补丁
I've initiated a temporary patch.
我可以把部分的电力传送到你的实验室
I was able to route partial power to your lab.
那传输机呢
Well, what about the transporters?
我还在弄
Still working on it.
恢复某一台之后再通知我
Yeah, well, let me know when you've got one online.
去实验室试试接进主机
Go to your lab and try to tap into the mainframe.
我走另一条楼梯
I'll try the other stairwells.
说不定也过不去  谁知道呢
They're probably blocked too, but who knows.
也许别的地方能上去
Maybe there's another way up.
好吧
All right.
中校
Colonel.
这也封死了吗
That one sealed too?
对  所有楼梯通道都是
Yeah, all the stairwell doors are.
正在想办法上星门室
Been trying to find a way up to the gate room
断电之后一直在想办法
Since the power went out.
我们也是
Yeah, so have we.
知道怎么回事吗
Any idea what's going on yet?
麦凯在找原因
Mckay's still working on it.
我估计用c-4能把门炸穿
I guess we could blow the door with c-4.
是啊  应该可以
Yeah, we probably will,
但至少得先找到门
But we're not there yet.
我去看看到底怎么回事
I need to know what we're up against
免得在这里死不瞑目
Before we go storming up there.
有发现吗
Any luck?
没啥
Not much.
不过你说中了  的确有人入侵亚特兰蒂斯
You're right, though. someone's taken over atlantis.
把主机黑了
They hacked into the mainframe.
我费了半天劲
I'm having a hard time
想进几个主要系统
Accessing several of the critical systems.
唯一能进去的还是只读的
And the ones that I can access are read-only.
你怎么
Hey, what're you...
你怎么这么快就到了
How did you get up here so fast?
我修好了几个
Oh, I was able to get some of the transporters
传输机
Back online again.
去星门室那层的修好了吗
What about the transporter on the gate room level?
很不幸  没有
No, sadly, no.
那层设了个封闭指令
There's a lockout code in place on that one.
监控录像
Surveillance cameras.
我们在控制室和星门室
We've got closed-circuit feeds
设置了独立回路参数
On the control room and the gate room.
只要没被锁在那里面
If you're not locked out of those as well.
它们不属于主系统
They're not critical systems.
我应该进得去
I should be able to access them if...
搞定
Got it.
小型飞船?
A puddle jumper?
那是谁
Who is that?
显然不是亚特兰蒂斯人
It's definitely not atlantis personnel.
能看到伍尔希的办公室吗
Can you get a feed on woolsey's office?
可以  等一下
Yeah, hang on.
我的老天
Oh, my god.
那不是
Is that...?
正是
Yeah.
迈克尔
Michael.
你好  泰勒
hello,teyla
你怎么进来的
How did you get here?
我从你们那儿"借"了个飞船
The ship I borrowed from your people.
附赠了丰富的信息
It has provided me with a wealth of information
和技术
And technology...
还送了我一把万能钥匙
And the key to infiltrating this base.
开这个门
Use this.
这是个数码录音笔
It's a digital voice recorder.
对它讲话  然后插入电脑
Speak into it, we'll plug it in,
你说的话就被自动记录下来
And your report will be automatically transcribed
然后和其他人的一起归档了
And filed with the others.
我也不太擅长说话
I'm not good at talking, either.
临时外来激活
Unscheduled off-world activation.
防护盾打开了吗
Is the shield raised?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
奈尔森中士的虹膜解除码
Major nelson's idc.
他们来早了
They're early.
按计划明天才到
Not due back until tomorrow.
好吧  让他们进来
All right, let them in.
怎么没停到飞船停泊舱去
It's not going up to the jumper bay.
怎么回事
What's wrong?
奈尔森中士  情况如何
Major nelson, what's your status?
什么东西
What is that?
紧急疏散
Get everybody out of here.
快疏散
Get 'em out now!
关闭所有紧急通道
Closing all immediate access doors.
入口护盾已经激活
I've activated the portal's shield.
很好
Good.
外网电源呢
What about the external power interface?
连接上了
We're connected.
星门室那层
The control room level
直接由飞船供源
Is now drawing power directly from the ship.
电击力场准备好了吗
Is the stun field holding?
好了
Yes.
我们上下两层保护起来
Two levels above and below us are protected.
可以开工了
Now we can get to work.
开什么工
Get to work on what?
原谅我
Forgive me.
忘了恭喜你
I forgot to congratulate you.
他叫什么
What's his name?
算了
No matter.
恐怕我们时间不多了
We don't have much time, I'm afraid.
我手下的变种人正在准备
My hybrids are preparing
启动亚特兰蒂斯的自毁系统
To activate atlantis' self-destruct device.
他们一启动  我们就离开
As soon as they do that, we will leave.
你要毁掉亚特兰蒂斯
You're going to destroy atlantis?
罪有应得
A punishment richly deserved.
我不指望你同意
Not that I expect you to agree with me.
不过别担心
But don't worry.
你的孩子会很安全
Your baby will be safe.
你不能带走我的孩子
You are not taking my son.
我会带走他  泰勒
Yes, teyla. I am.
你的孩子对我很重要
You know how important your child is to me.
你和他父亲赋予了他强大的力量
His father and you have given him a powerful gift
若能被我所用
That I will utilize
我就能彻底控制那些变种人了
To exert greater control over my legion of hybrids.
想要变强  没他不行
He is the key to increasing my strength,
他将使我统领整个星系
Securing my reign over the galaxy.
别做你的帝王梦了
Your "reign" is over.
你别想活着带走他
You will not make it out of here alive.
我的同伴肯定会
My people will make certain--
够了  够了
Enough! enough.
你以为你削弱了我的力量
You think you've weakened me.
你毁了我的基地
You've destroyed my facilities,
毁了我的研究  但你不能
Ruined much of my research, but you cannot--
你不能
You cannot--
动摇我的决心
Weaken my resolve.
别犯傻了  泰勒
Make no mistake, teyla.
我前所未有的强大
I am as strong now as I have ever been.
看看周围
Look around you.
我控制着亚特兰蒂斯
I am in control of atlantis,
就是在这儿
The very place
我依稀记得被你们杀掉的滋味
Where your people ended my life as I knew it.
是时候回来
It's only fitting that I return...
让它永远的从银河系里
To extinguish this blight from the galaxy
消失了
Once and for all.
我还以为迈克尔死了
I thought michael was dead.
是啊
As did i.
咱们不是把他的船都炸飞了吗
I mean, we blew up his ship, right?
就是他偷了我们的飞船
He's the one who stole our jumper,
在我们炸他之前
Used it to escape from his cruiser
从舰上逃走了
Before we could destroy it.
顽强如小强
He's like a cockroach.
每次就快踩着时
Every time you try to step on him,
就溜的没影了
He just skitters away.
好了  我们得开始行动了
All right, we need to get moving.
罗恩  你带人从这边楼梯走
Lorne, you and your team take this stairwell.
我们走这条
My team will take this stairwell.
在各自位置守好
We move into position.
等我信号就炸门
You wait for my mark to blast the door.
我们冲进去  夺回星门室
We head up, retake the gate room.
麦凯  你跟着我
Mckay, you're with me.
泽兰卡留守  努力解码
Zelenka, stay here, try to figure this thing out.
遵命
Certainly.
对迈克尔绝不能手软
We're giving michael no quarter.
击中他  就别停
If you get a shot at him, take it.
确保弄死他
Make sure he's dead.
行动
Let's move.
我得跟你谈谈
I must speak with you.
我们还是无法激活
We are still having difficulty
自毁系统
With the self-destruct device.
为什么
Why?
我说过
As I told you,
密码比我们预计的
The encryption is much more complex
复杂很多
Than we had anticipated.
我们试了几组质因子算法
We have run several integer factorization algorithms.
都不行
Nothing has worked so far.
那就继续算
Keep at it.
算多久
For how long?
直到算出来为止
As long as it takes.
他们突破我们的防御
It is only a matter of time
是迟早的事
Before the others figure out a way through our defenses.
我知道
I know.
那你就赶在他们之前
But you will have solved the encryption problem
解开密码
Before then.
我们已经找到孩子了
We have the baby.
没必要再耗在这儿
We don't have to remain here.
那装置没激活我们就不走
We are not leaving until that device is armed.
出问题了吧
Problems?
没什么解决不了的
Nothing that can't be dealt with.
你应该知道谢帕德中校
You do know that colonel sheppard
一定在组织突击队
Is no doubt preparing strike teams
要夺回星门室
To retake the gate room.
当然
Of course,
或许在我们谈话的时候  他们就会来
Probably moving them into place as we speak.
别担心
Don't worry.
他们进不来
They're not getting in here.
少校  你那边情况怎样
Major, what's your status?
回中校  C-4准备好  只等你的指示
C-4 is in place, colonel. ready when you are.
准备爆破
Fire in the hole.
准备
On my mark.
三  二  一
Three, two, one,
爆破
Mark.
行动
Move!
慢着  数据显示上面有巨大能量
Whoa, whoa, we're picking up a serious energy reading up ahead.
怎么回事
What is it?
不清楚  搞清楚前不要轻举妄动
I don't know, but we should stop until I do.
罗恩少校  停下
Major lorne, hold up.
谢帕德中校  罗恩少校晕倒了
Colonel sheppard, major lorne is down.
发生什么事了
What happened?
不知道
I don't know.
可能是撞到某种力场
I think he hit some kind of force field.
他还活着  但没有知觉
He's alive, but unconscious.
把他抬出去  撤退
Get him out of there and fall back.
看来他还建了一个力场
Looks like he's got himself a force field.
他要不那么勤奋  早废了
He's nothing if not annoyingly industrious.
说得有理  我们现在该怎办
All right, what do we do?
关了它
Well, we disable it.
怎么做
How?
问...得好
good question
我不断检查收到的能量读数
I've been examining the energy reading we picked up,
看来迈克尔改良过了
And it appears that michael has somehow managed to modify
幽灵人的电流脉冲技术
The wraith stun-pulse technology
结合了小型飞船隐形技术
And integrate it with the puddle jumper cloaking mechanism--
创造出了所谓的"电击泡泡"
Creating a kind of "stun-bubble"--
不  是力场
No, a force field
围绕在控制室和星门室周围
Around the control room and the gate room.
听着  只要它在那儿  我们别想进去
Look, while it's in place, we're not getting in there.
我知道
Well, I know that.
你还没告诉我怎么关了它
What you haven't told me is how we're gonna turn it off.
我们还没想出对策
Because we haven't figured that out yet.
这得靠技巧才行
Look, it's going to be very tricky.
迈克尔用小型飞船
Yeah, you see, michael is using the puddle jumper
作为外部电源
As an external power source,
不仅供给控制室和星门室
Not only for the control room and the gate room,
还要支持"电击泡泡"的运作
But also, he's using it to power the stun-bubble--
够了  别提那个"电击泡泡"
Okay, enough with the "stun-bubble."
这表达很准确
That's an accurate description--
不  这表达很白痴
No, it's a stupid description--
兄弟们
Guys, guys...
听着  问题是
Look, the point is
如果我们要停止那个电击...
That if we want to disable the stun--
力场的运作
The force field,
我们要先切断飞船的能源
Then we first need to disable the power from the jumper.
或者  我们另行其道
Or we figure out a way
切断迈克尔对主机的控制
To override the mainframe lockouts that michael has in place.
这又要怎么做
All right, how's that going?
不可行
It's not.
暂时
Not yet.
继续努力吧
Keep working on it.
我去看看罗恩
I'm going to check on lorne.
发生什么事
What happened?
一艘小型飞船突袭
That puddle jumper that came through...
发出某种电波
It sent out some kind of stun wave,
把所有人都击晕了
Knocked everybody out.
所有亚特兰蒂斯人
All of atlantis?
不清楚
I don't know.
可能吧
Probably.
别担心  他们快醒了
Don't worry, they'll wake up soon.
每个人的抵抗力不同
Everyone has a different level of resistance.
来
Here.
谁做的
Who would do this?
不知道  我正想查个清楚
I don't know. that's what I want to find out.
你能打开那扇门吗
Can you open that door?
可以
I think so.
好的  上
Good. do it.
还是没反应
Still nothing.
泰勒  有段时间你还是挺理解我的
There was a time you understood me, teyla.
我被你们的人带来
When your people brought me here,
注射逆转录病毒  将我变成人类
Gave me the retrovirus that turned me into a human,
只有你同情我
You alone showed me compassion.
只有你有良心
You were the voice of conscience.
我反复思量
I've given this a great deal of thought.
我...
I've...
我想还你个人情
I'm willing to return the favor.
我很想带你走
I would very much like for you to come with me.
你可以照顾你的孩子
You can care for your child,
我们照看你们俩
And I will care for the both of you.
我宁愿死
I would rather die.
我保证
I promise...
我不会伤害你们的
I will not harm either of you.
泰勒
Teyla...
你得相信我
You have to believe me.
我不会相信一个杀人犯说的话
I can not trust the word of a murderer.
你怎么就不开窍
Why can't you understand?
我这么做是有苦衷的
I have become what I am out of necessity,
生存所逼
The need to survive!
你这么做是为了复仇
You became what you are out of vengeance.
难道在你的世界  罪人就不该受罚吗
Do you not punish criminals in your world?
正义就不能得到伸张吗
Are they not brought to justice?
对你来说这是正义吗
Is this justice to you?
杀死银河系数以千计的
Killing hundreds of thousands of innocent people
无辜人民
Across this galaxy?
要不是你们要用我来做
They would not be dead
那个邪恶的试验
Had you not made me the subject
他们就不会死
Of your vicious experiment!
你的双手沾满他们的鲜血
Their blood is on your hands!
你自己选
It's your choice.
跟我走生存下去  或者留下来等死
You can come with me and live, or remain here and die.
无论如何  我都要带走你的孩子
Either way, I'm taking your child.
我们得炸掉飞船
We need to blow up the jumper.
如果我们炸了它
If we blow it up,
切断了电源  就停止了力场
We cut the power and disable the force field,
对吧
Right?
好计划  我只是不确定
Great plan-- I'm just not entirely clear
你究竟要怎么炸毁那艘飞船
On how you intend on doing the actual blowing up.
用远程遥控飞船去撞
Fire a drone at it.
不行
We can't.
备用电池提供的能量
The chair room requires far more power
无法支撑主室的能量消耗
Than the auxiliary battery units can provide.
我勉强能调足够的能量到这实验室
I was barely able to bring enough power into this lab,
更别提还要支撑几个
Let alone the few transporters
刚修好的传输机
I could bring online.
好的  那就用飞船
All right, then, we'll take a jumper.
我再一次问  怎么做
Again, I come back to my question of how?
我们去不了飞船舱
We have no way of getting to the jumper bay.
那我们就去水下基地找一架
We'll take one from the underwater bay.
飞到塔楼上
Fly it up to the tower,
然后扔个飞弹出去
Fire a drone through the window,
炸掉迈克尔的飞船
And take out michael's jumper.
怎么了
What?
没  没  听着挺好的
Uh, no, no, no, that's a good plan,
除了一个小问题
Except I see one small problem--
水下停泊舱
The underwater jumper bay
只有几架飞船
Only has a couple of jumpers in it.
我们只要一架啊
Well, we only need one.
问题是
Yes, well, the thing is--
大多都因长期泡水
Both of them were severely damaged
坏得厉害
In the flood.
没有哪架还能飞
Neither of them is able to fly.
都2年了  瑞迪克  麦凯早修好了
That was two years ago, radek. mckay already fixed them.
不会吧...
Oh, you've got to be kidding me...
我正准备修
It was the next thing on my list.
你说过你要去修的
You said you were going to fix them.
我知道  我准备要修的  真的
I know, and I was getting to it, I swear.
2年了呢
And you had two years!
我忙的很
I was busy!
或许我们应该下去看看
Perhaps we should go
还能不能修个一两架
And see if we can fix one of them.
好主意
That's a good idea,
但你给我留在这儿
But I want you stay here
想办法切断迈克尔的锁定
To try to override michael's lockouts.
为什么我不能留下做这个
Why don't I stay here and work on that?
泽兰卡可以和你去修飞船
Zelenka can go with you to the jumper bay.
因为你一定要去
Because I want you to come with me
修飞船
And fix those jumpers
你2年前说过
Like you said you were going to do
你要去修的
Two years ago.
走吧
Let's go.
希望有传输机送我们去
Please tell me there's a transporter.
有的
Yes.
不过  离舱远的很
Well, not by the jumper bay,
两层下面有一个传输机
But there's one two levels down.
太好了
That'll do.
干得好
Nice.
你会打?
You can fight.
打过5年拳击
Five years of kick-boxing.
这消息不错
That's good to know.
发生了什么事
What happened?
是迈克尔和他的变种人
It's Michael and his hybrids.
我数出三个
I counted three of 'em.
不知道后面是不是还有更多的
I'm not sure how many more there are.
估计不会太多
Probably not too many--
毕竟是乘飞船过来
They all had to fit in that jumper.
除非他们走过来
Unless more came through on foot afterward.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
先想办法去武器库
Try to get to the armory,
然后回来夺回星门室
come back and retake the gate room.
听起来计划不错
Sounds like a plan.
你们两个  跟我们来
You two, come with us.
你就和他们呆一起  安抚下他们
Stay here with them, keep all of them calm
如果还有变种人出现
And, uh, if any more hybrids show up,
就像刚刚那样做
just do what you did earlier.
再跟你说一遍  这很紧急
...speak with you again. It's urgent.
和他待一起
Stay with him.
怎么了
What is it?
我们终于破译了
We were finally able to
自毁装置的密码
decipher the encryption on the self-destruct device.
很好
Good.
准备起飞
Prepare the ship to leave.
准备启动自毁装置
We'll arm the self-destruct,
然后在我们离开前的瞬间
And switch the power back to Atlantis' systems
把电源切回到亚特兰蒂斯的系统
a split-second before we leave.
时机一定要精准
The timing of the switch must be precise.
我不想他们有任何机会
I don't want to give them any opportunity
解除装置
to disarm the device.
我会计算好的
I'll make the calculations.
计划有变
Change of plans.
我们不去武器库了
We're not going to the armory.
为什么  发生什么事了
Why? What happened?
他们启动了自毁装置
They armed the self-destruct.
伍尔希先生  能否请你回到其他人那里
Mr. Woolsey, would you please head back to the others?
谢帕德中校  我是泰勒
Colonel Sheppard, this is Teyla.
能听得到吗
Can you hear me?
约翰  我是泰勒  请回话
John, this is Teyla. Please respond.
谢帕...
Colonel Shep--
谢帕德中校
Colonel Sheppard.
若楠在控制室
Ronon is in the control room.
正和迈克尔打着呢
He's fighting with Michael!
我们快到飞船舱了  有情况随时通报
We're almost at the jumper bay. Keep us posted.
泰勒  快跑
Teyla, run!
泰勒
Teyla!
你还好吗
Are you all right?
还好
Yes.
但是若楠需要帮忙
But Ronon needs our help.
我们必须尽快回到控制室
We need to get back up to the control room.
瑞迪克?  那里发生了什么事
Radek? Tell us what's going on up there.
我说不好  若楠倒下了
I-- I can't tell. Ronon is down.
可能昏过去了
He might just be unconscious.
他醒过来了就告诉我
Tell me when he comes to.
我们进展怎么样
What have we got?
就像我说的  两个飞船都坏了
It's like I said--both of the jumpers are toast.
这个有一大堆的问题
This one's got a whole whack of problems,
首先就是没有能源
starting with zero power.
你的意思是说另外一个有能源的对不对
You said the other jumper's got power, right?
对  不过好不了多少
Yeah, but not much else.
驾驶舱不能用  也没有飞弹
Drive pods won't extend, there's no drones...
可是这艘有飞弹
This one's got drones.
如果我们把能源弄过来
So if we bring power over to this,
这样驾驶舱就可以用了  对吧
We can get drive pods working, right?
你想让我把两个船上能用的部件
You want me to harvest parts from both jumpers,
就这么拼成一个可以用的飞船?
Cobble together a fix so one of them will work?
可行吗
Is it possible?
我怀疑
Doubtful.
但也是有可能的...
But maybe...
怎么说都有很多工作
A long shot at best.
很好  开始吧
Perfect. Get to it.
要多久  15分钟?
What do you need, 15 minutes?
真好  真是好极了
Great, just great.
传输机也被关了
Must've locked out the transporters.
我们要去控制室
We need to get to the control room.
这太危险了  没有武器就不能去
It's too dangerous.Not without weapons.
最近的楼梯在哪里
Where's the nearest stairwell?
转角那儿  这边
Around the corner. This way.
我走前面
Let me lead.
好了  输好了
Okay, give 'er.
驾驶舱可以用了
Drive pods are go.
好了  我们差不多了
All right, now we're getting somewhere.
有能源  有生命支持系统  有...
I got juice, I got life support, I got--
不是吧
Oh, come on!
怎么了
What?
武器装置没连上
The weapons won't come online.
为什么
Why not?
我不知道
I don't know.
那就找原因  我们需要飞弹
Well, figure it out. we need those drones.
她在哪里
Where is she?
我们不知道
We don't know.
我们都找遍了
We searched everywhere.
你是想说她就这样消失了吗
Are you telling me she just disappeared?
我是说我们找遍了几乎
I'm saying that we searched every room and corridor
每个房间和走道
Within the stun field.
哪儿都找不到
We couldn't find her anywhere.
她对这个城市很了解
She knows this city well.
一定是躲在哪里了
She's hiding somewhere.
她在和我玩
She's toying with me!
我们会继续找的
We'll keep looking.
不用了  我来处理
No. I'll handle this.
你要怎么做
What are you going to do?
把她逼出来
Flush her out.
是亚特兰蒂斯的自毁系统
That's Atlantis' self-destruct.
迈克尔要炸了这个城市
Michael's going to blow up the city.
我们有多少时间
How much time do we have?
他设置为10分钟
He set it for 10 minutes.
那你要多久
How much time do you need
能把飞弹弄好
before you get those drones working?
如果真能弄好
If I can get them working at all,
10分钟也不够啊
A lot more than 10 minutes!
好吧  那就别理它了
All right, forget about it.
你  你干什么
What are you-- what are you doing?
开飞船去撞塔楼
Gonna fly the jumper and crash it into the tower.
撞上去?
Crash it?
这是最好的逼出迈克尔的方法
It's our best chance of taking out Michael's jumper.
可也把自己也搭进去了
Not to mention taking out yourself.
我以前开飞船撞过塔楼
I have crashed jumpers into the tower before.
像这样的可没有
Not like this you haven't.
除了没有武器
Look, in addition to the weapons,
还有惯性的问题
The inertial dampeners are out.
为了给迈克尔的飞船
You'll need to impact michael's jumper
造成足够的破坏
with enough force to do some serious damage,
你撞上去的速度必须非常快
which means a lot of speed when you hit that tower.
这根本就是自杀行为
Look, this is a suicide mission.
泰勒
Teyla...
我知道你听得到我
I know you can hear me.
这个警报声  如果你不清楚的话
That alarm, if you're not aware,
是亚特兰蒂斯的自毁装置
is Atlantis' self-destruct device.
我已经启动了  设为10分钟
I've armed it, set it for 10 minutes.
也就是说你有10分钟的时间
That is the amount of time you have
来考虑我提出的建议
to consider the offer I'm about to make.
如果你能交出自己和孩子
If you will surrender yourself and your child to me,
我就关闭装置
I'll disarm the device,
饶了这个基地上的人一命
sparing the lives of everyone on this base.
如果不的话...你  你的孩子
If not... you, your baby,
所有人都要死
And everyone else will die.
好了  你可以走了
Okay, you're good to go.
确保塔楼塌下来的时候
Make sure that strike team is ready to move
突击队准备好出发了
as soon as that field drops.
我会的
I will.
出舱的时候
Don't accelerate too fast
不要加速的太快
coming out of the jumper bay.
如果太快
If you hit the gas too hard,
你会像煎饼一样扁的
you're going to flatten like a pancake.
好的
Right.
怎么了
What?
只是...
Well, it's just...
你现在做的...
What you're about to do is...
又不是第一次了
Yeah. It's not like it's the first time.
我做过几次这种自杀任务了
How many suicide missions have I flown?
我不知道  数不清了都
I don't know. I lost count.
好了  出发了
Well, there you go.
好吧
All right, well, you know...
希望还有更多
Here's to many more.
罗德尼?
Rodney?
瑞迪克  啥事
Yeah, radek. go ahead.
我终于知道
I've finally figured out
该怎么绕过迈克尔的封闭指令了
How to override some of michael's lockout codes.
太棒了
That's great.
那能把自毁装置关了么
Can you shut down the self-destruct?
还不行  这个还需要点时间
No. no, no, that will take a little bit more time.
不过  我知道怎么去星门室了
I have, however, managed to get the access doors to the gate room open.
这个  并不是什么好事啊
Well, that does us absolutely no good.
力场仍然在工作中诶
I mean, the stun field is still in effect.
那星门室那一层的传输器呢
What about the transporter on the gate room level?
还不行
Uh... no, no,
那个也没办法控制
I still don't have control of that, either.
真服了你了
For crying out loud--
拜托  我已经尽力了
I'm sorry, I'm doing the best I can.
迈克尔设置了许多高级密码
Michael has placed several highly encrypted codes--
那这样吧
Look, just--
防护盾呢  能不能降下来一些
What about the gate shield? can you lower it?
这个行
Yes. that I can do.
太好了
Great.
你也不用玩什么敢死队了
You don't have to do your kamikaze run.
怎么了
Why not?
直接飞向塔楼  尽量靠近
Just fly to the tower, get in proximity,
然后随便向哪个星球呼叫下
Dial the dhd to a random planet,
然后再让瑞迪克把防护盾降下来一些
We'll have radek lower the gate shield,
直接制造个漩涡
Allowing the vortex
把迈克尔的飞船给冲出来
To obliterate michael's puddle jumper...
或者逼出个大部分也行
Or most of it.
这主意倒是不错
Now, that's a good plan.
你去哪
Where are you going?
你来驾驶飞船
You're gonna fly it.
我就能去带领突击队
That frees me up to lead the strike team.
听你说的  很简单了
You said it yourself-- it's simple enough.
只要拨号就可以了
You just dial the gate.
这个我能行
I guess I can do that.
要小心加速器
Go easy on the accelerator.
瑞迪克  准备好听我的指示
Radek, get ready to drop that shield on my mark.
对对...
Right...
我们没多少时间了
We don't have much time.
得赶紧离开这里
We need to leave this place.
时间有限  泰勒
Time is short, teyla.
我不明白
I don't understand--
这选择又不难
I would think the choice is an easy one...
想想你的孩子
If nothing else, consider your child.
你就一直这么藏着
By remaining in hiding,
就相当于判了他死刑
You are sentencing him to die.
有哪个母亲会做这种事
What kind of mother would do such a thing?
他有机会活下去的
He has a chance to live.
你们俩都有
Both of you do.
跟我来吧  泰勒
Come with me, teyla.
相信我
Trust me--
我不会伤害你们的
I will not harm either of you.
我也不会伤害亚特兰蒂斯
And I will not harm atlantis.
我向你保证
You have my word.
关掉自毁装置
Turn off the self-destruct system.
泰勒?
Teyla?
你希望我相信你么
You want me to trust you?
那就证明给我看
Then show me you mean what you say.
关掉自毁装置
Turn off the self-destruct system,
我就跟你走
And I will come with you.
我现在已经升空
All right, I'm in the air...
向中心塔楼飞去
Approaching the central tower.
收到
Copy that.
泽兰卡  你准备好了吗
Zelenka, you ready?
随时待命
Ready when you are.
迈克尔  你听到我说的话了吗
Michael, can you hear me?
只剩不到2分钟
Less than two minutes.
我们得走了  马上
We need to go. now.
是的  泰勒
Yes, teyla.
我听见了
I hear you.
你真让我失望
You disappoint me.
我不会阻止你走你自己选择的路
So I will leave you to the fate you have chosen.
但是我也不会空手而归
But I'm not leaving alone.
你应该知道
You should know
我已经采集了你儿子的DNA
That I've already collected your son's dna...
重新克隆一个虽然需要更多时间
Cloning him will require additional time,
耽误我的计划
Delaying the implementation of my plan,
但是你知道的  我不会退缩的
But as you well know, I will not be deterred.
再见  泰勒
Good-bye, teyla.
你在干吗
What are you doing?
收集最后一份战果
Collecting one last prize.
就位  准备拨号
I'm in position. ready to dial.
瑞迪克  降下防护盾
Radek, drop the shield.
防护盾降下来了  罗德尼  出发
The shield's down! go, rodney!
不!
No!
力场在慢慢减弱了
The stun field is neutralized!
那自毁装置呢  破坏掉了没
What about the self-destruct? is it disabled?
是的  飞船能源一关闭  它就停了
Yes, yes. it shut off when the jumper's power was cut.
好的  那我现在掉头回去了
Good. I'm heading back.
你继续恢复城市能源
Go ahead and reboot the city's power.
正在处理中了
Yes, I'm already doing it.
去找个医生
Get a medic!
瑞迪克  关掉舱门
Close the jumper bay doors, radek!
艾米丽亚
Amelia...
帮我照看下图门行么
Will you take care of torren for me?
好的
Of course.
不要让任何人离开
Make sure no one leaves.
泰勒
Ah! teyla!
我们凯勒的小调皮病号感觉如何?
How's dr. keller's most cantankerous patient?
你在开玩笑呢吧
You've got to be kidding me.
你能出院了
You get released,
而我还要再待一天么
And I gotta stay here another day?
因为我只是滚了几级台阶而已
Because I only fell down a flight of stairs.
而你  我的朋友  可是被人从楼上推了下来
You, my friend, were hurled from a much greater height.
只有个脑震荡  算是你运气好了
You're lucky you only suffered a concussion
没把脖子摔断了
And didn't break your neck.
没什么  我很好
Nothing. I'm fine.
我知道你好
I know you are.
不过还是要听医生的话
But listen to the doctor.
不过呢  我主要是想来
Anyway, I just wanted to drop by
表扬一下你的模范作用
And commend you for your exemplary work.
你的临危不惧
Your courage in the face of danger
始终能让我惊讶
Continues to amaze
或者容我说  让我敬佩
And, dare I say, inspire me.
多谢夸奖
Thanks.
好好休息
Get some rest.
不要担心
And don't worry.
你的队员会等你康复的
Your team's not going anywhere without you.
这倒提醒我了
That reminds me.
我知道  这次迈克尔对亚城的攻击
I know michael attacking the city
并不算什么正式的任务
Isn't really a mission,
不过我还是弄了份报告
But, uh, I filed a report anyways.
非常好
Splendid.
谢谢
Thank you.
任务报告
Mission report--
迈克尔入侵亚特兰蒂斯
Michael invaded atlantis,
试图炸毁它
Tried to blow it up.
我们阻止了他
We stopped him.
报告完毕
End of report.
长远来看
Take a good long look,
你肯定是只能咬着我的车尾巴啦
'cause soon you're going to see nothing but taillights.
好办法  赛车手
Nice try, speed racer.
对不起啊
I'm sorry.
对不起啦  我们只是...
Sorry, we were just, you know...
谁赢了
Who's winning?
我
I am.
疝气还没好呢?
Still colicky, huh?
他都一天没睡了
He was awake all day.
也总是睡不着
Refused to take a nap.
这很正常啊
That's not surprising.
晚上不是都在睡了么
He got a full night's sleep.
是啊  这很让我惊讶的
Yes, it's remarkable.
他从头到尾都在睡着
He slept through the entire ordeal.
他从来没有这样整夜睡下来过
He hasn't slept through a whole night in...
从来没有
Ever.
以后可以睡安稳咯
Well, he can rest easy now,
既然迈克尔已经就这样消失在历史版图中
'cause michael's finally out of the picture.
可是以后肯定还会有第二个迈克尔
Unfortunately, there will be somebody else to take his place.
我敢肯定
Of this, I am certain.
他有个超级妈妈的
He's got super mom watching his back.
要说我  没事的
If you ask me, he's in good hands.
图门  想看看我
Torren, do you want to watch me
是怎么打败罗德尼的么
Kick rodney's ass?
帮忙遮下宝宝的眼睛
Actually, you may want to cover the child's eyes,
因为他会输得很难看的哦
Because this could get ugly.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
当然
Yeah.
一  二
One... two--